RG 103, Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company
Connecticut State Library
- Publications File, circa 1850-1980; T001481; 6.75 cubic feet
  - Printed Materials (Company-Related), 1851-1970
    - Publications/External (Box 70)
      - Newspaper articles
        - The Waterbury Republican, "Marking 100 Years for the Gun that Settled America's West, 1936 July 16, 2 copies. (Box 70B)
        - Hartford Courant magazine, "Superb Literary Memorial to Col. Colt", Book Review of Haven & Belden's A History of the Colt Revolver, 1940 September 22. (Box 70B)
        - Orlando Sunday Sentinnial-Star, "The First Six-Gun Man", 1953 June 7, p. 16-D. (Box 70B)
        - The Sunday News, "Colt's Submarine Battery Tests off Staten Island", D. Owen, 1954 November 14., 3 copies (Box 70B)
        - The (Waterbury) Sunday Republican, "Return of 'The Peacemaker', Gun That Won the West", 1956 January 8, magazine section. (Box 70B)
        - "The Birth of the Six-Shooter". (Box 70B)
        - Hartford Courant, "Texas to Honor Colt 'Glory Guns' in Centennial Exposition, Dallas", 1864 February 27. (Box 70B)
        - Hartford Courant, "Machine Guns Manufacture/Hartford", also "25 Year Employee Club", 1924 July. (Box 70B)
  - Printed Materials/Employee-Related, 1871-1952; 2 folders + 2 volumes (Box 71)
    Includes many items for use within the Armory, throughout employment with Company, such as an office benefits booklet and company procedures, invitations to Company dances and lectures, employee and exit passes, booklet with agreement between Union members and administration officials 1941, time cards and a 1935 listing of telephone numbers. No exact dates. There are a number of items relating to clubs and committees within the Company. These are as follows: 1890 programme of the Wheel Club Tournament (with Colt's Bicycle Club); a menu from event sponsored by the Colt Pistol and Revolver Club; the Constitution of the Colt Club; 2 booklets of the Colt Hammerless Gun Club, 1894, 1903; and a booklet of the Machine Gun Associates, 1946. Also, an 1871 handwritten list of contributors to the Chicago Relief Fund (presented in 1913 by Sam Walker, past employee). There are also two bound items--the 1907-1911 papers of the Tuberculosis Committee, and the 1919-1930 papers of the Arms Club (in looseleaf binder). Also, the letters to members of the 25-year club, 1934-1940 (inclusive).
  - Printed Materials/External, 1851-1980; 2 folders
    - Items collected by Colt Company of own dealers and trade, 1 folder (Box 71)
      - Senate Report advocating Colt's repeating pistols - distributed by H. E. Dimick with cover for advertising, 1851 January 30 (Box 71)
      - Illustrated booklet of "The Evolution of the Gun," E. C. Meacham, 1890 (Box 71)
      - Bucheimer, manufacturers of leather goods such as holsters, police equipment and hunting accessories, 1905 (Box 71)
      - "Gun-play," by Texas Jack Sullivan, 1931 (Box 71)
      - H & D Folsom Arms Co. NY - trade prices, 1934 May 15 (Box 71)
      - 125th anniversary programme - E. K. Tryon & Co., 1811-1936, 2 copies (Box 71)
      - List of members of the Armor and Arms Club, 1980 (Box 71)
      - Cherry's Sporting Goods, Illinois - Commemorative Gun Listing, undated (Box 71)
      - The Peters Cartridge Company, Ohio, undated (Box 71)
      - The Mills Woven Cartridge Belt/T. C. Orndorff - manufacturer, undated (Box 71)
      - Frontier Colts/Hy Hunter, undated (Box 71)
      - Hi-Standard's Flite-King parts price list, undated (Box 71)
    - Items collected by Colt Company of other organizations and various events, 1 folder (Box 71)
      Includes 1916 "40 Days at Colt's," a booklet documenting Aberthaw's construction of a building at Colt's, items from the Wadsworth Atheneum; 1935 Conncticut Tercentenary celebration programe; a catalogue from Steinfeld's 3rd annual gunshow (1960 August) and "Eighty Years at Pratt & Whitney"; American Swedish Monthly (with an article on Pratt & Whitney, and press release and advertisements, 1966-1969.
- Mahron Collection, 1871-1934; T003190; 46 cubic feet
  - Sales Journals
    - 1875 January-1879 December, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1880 January-1882 December, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1883 December-1886 December, 1 volume (Box 3)
    - 1887 January-1890 December, 1 volume (Box 4)
    - 1891 January-1898 December, 1 volume (Box 5)
    - 1898 October-1907 December, 1 volume (Box 6)
    - 1908 January-1915 April, 1 volume (Box 7)
    - 1919 May-1923 July, 1 volume (Box 8)
  - Sales Books
    - 1887 January-1891 December, 1 volume (Box 9)
    - 1890 November-1891 July, 1 volume (Box 10)
    - 1891 July-December, 1 volume (Box 11)
    - 1892 January-August, 1 volume (Box 12)
    - 1894 January-December, 1 volume (Box 13)
    - 1894 October-1895 July, 1 volume (Box 14)
    - 1895 July-1896 March, 1 volume (Box 15)
    - 1896 April-December, 1 volume (Box 16)
    - 1897 January-September, 1 volume (Box 17)
    - 1897 October-1898 April, 1 volume (Box 18)
    - 1898 May-December, 1 volume (Box 19)
    - 1898 December-1899 July, 1 volume (Box 20)
    - 1899 May-1901 May, 1 volume (Box 21)
    - 1900 February-August, 1 volume (Box 22)
    - 1900 August-1901 April, 1 volume (Box 23)
    - 1900 August-1901 April, 1 volume (Box 24)
    - 1901 February-May, 1 volume (Box 25)
    - 1901 May-December, 1 volume (Box 26)
    - 1901 July-December, 1 volume (Box 27)
    - 1901 December, 1 volume (Box 28)
    - 1912 August-1913 June, 1 volume (Box 29)
    - 1912 December-1913 June, 1 volume (Box 30)
  - General Expense Account Ledgers
    - 1872 January-1878 December, 1 volume (Box 31)
    - 1876-1881, 1 volume (Box 32)
      Present in donations but not on donor's list of items.
    - 1882 January-1886 December, 1 volume (Box 33)
    - 1887 January-1888 December, 1 volume (Box 34)
    - 1892 July-1894 March
      On donor's list of items but not present in donation.
    - 1915 July-1919 April, 1 volume (Box 35)
      Museum purchase, accession no. 1994.2.
    - 1923 August-1926 December, 1 volume (Box 36)
    - 1929 January-1930 December
    - 1929 January-1931 December, 1 volume (Box 37)
    - 1927 January-1928 December, 1 volume (Box 38)
  - Inventory Analyses
    - 1903 January-1906 October, 1 volume (Box 39)
    - 1907 January-1911 January, 1 volume (Box 39)
  - Rent Books
    - 1892-1901, 1 volume (Box 40)
    - 1901-1909, 1 volume (Box 40)
  - Account Ledgers
    - 1871 January-1876 December, 1 volume (Box 41)
    - 1891 January-1894 December, 1 volume (Box 42)
    - 1902 June-1905 January, 1 volume (Box 43)
    - 1905 February-1909 March, 1 volume (Box 43)
    - 1909 April-1912 June, 1 volume (Box 43)
    - 1912 July-1914 December, 1 volume (Box 44)
    - 1915 January-1917 August, 1 volume (Box 44)
    - 1917 August-1919 October, 1 volume (Box 45)
    - 1919 November-1922 April, 1 volume (Box 45)
    - 1926 December-1932 December, 1 volume (Box 46)
  - Cash Books
    - 1890 November-1892 June, 1 volume (Box 47)
    - 1890 November-1892 June
      This is a second copy that was on donor's list of items, but not present in donation.
    - 1892 July-1894 March, 1 volume (Box 47)
    - 1894 April-1895 December, 1 volume (Box 47)
    - 1896 January-1897 October, 1 volume (Box 48)
    - 1897 November-1899 June
    - 1899 July-1900 December, 1 volume (Box 48)
    - 1900 December-1902 May, 1 volume (Box 48)
    - 1903 February-1904 July, 1 volume (Box 49)
    - 1904 August-1905 December, 1 volume (Box 49)
    - 1909 October-1911 July, 1 volume (Box 49)
    - 1913 April-1914 October, 1 volume (Box 50)
    - 1921 June-1922 February, 1 volume (Box 50)
    - 1921 June-1922 February (second copy), 1 volume (Box 50)
    - 1922 February-1922 October, 1 volume (Box 51)
    - 1923 July-1924 April, 1 volume (Box 51)
    - 1931 January-1932 December, 1 volume (Box 52)
    - 1933 January-1934 December, 1 volume (Box 52)
  - Factory Inventories (Box 53)
    - 1894, 1 volume (Box 53)
    - 1895, 1 volume (Box 53)
    - 1896, 1 volume (Box 54)
    - 1896 (second copy), 1 volume (Box 54)
    - 1898, 1 volume (Box 55)
    - 1899 (photocopy), 1 volume (Box 55)
    - 1900, 1 volume (Box 56)
    - 1901, 1 volume (Box 56)
    - 1902, 1 volume (Box 57)
    - 1903, 1 volume (Box 57)
    - 1904, 1 volume (Box 58)
    - 1906, 1 volume (Box 58)
    - 1907, 1 volume (Box 59)
  - Government Order Journals
    - 1909 January-1914 September, 1 volume (Box 60)
    - 1914 October-1920 November, 1 volume (Box 61)
  - Special Order Ledgers
    - 1914 August-1916 November, 1 volume (Box 61)
    - 1916 November-1919 October, 1 volume (Box 61)
  - Serial Number Ledgers
    - Model 1895 Machine Gun, 1895 December-1916 January; 1 volume (Box 62)
    - Baxter Steam Engines, 1871; 1 volume (Box 62)
    - Baxter Steam Engines, 1872-1883; 1 volume (Box 62)
  - Printing Press Order Journals
    - 1888
    - 1888-1890, 1 volume (Box 63)
  - Casting Order Book, 1890; 1 volume (Box 63)
  - Index Books
    - Number 1, 1 volume (Box 64)
    - Number 16, 1 volume (Box 64)
    - Number 18, 1 volume (Box 64)
    - Number 19, 1 volume (Box 64)
  - Consignment and Sales Book: Portable Disc Engines, 1886-1899; 1 volume (Box 65)
    Museum purchase, accession no. 1996.308
- Addenda, 1810-1948; 4.25 cubic feet
  - 2000-006, 1.75 cubic feet (1 oversize flat box)
    - Cash Book, 1885-1889
  - T000731, 2 cubic feet
    - Submarine battery tag 10 53 (Box 1)
    - Bills and receipts, Union Company, 1810-1822 (Box 1)
    - Misplaced correspondence, 1861, 1883-1890, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Wild Bill Hickok letter to wife and marriage certificate, 1876 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified correspondence, circa 1880-1895 (Box 1)
    - Blank stock certificates, Litchfield Bank, New Haven, Middletown, and Willimantic Railroad (Box 1)
    - Drawings, 1852 (Box 2)
  - 1992-018
    - Photographs of Colt guns, 10 items
  - 1994-038, 0.5 cubic feet
    - Index to collection
    - Material specification, 1948 January 27
    - Material specification, 1948 March 10, 1948 March 23
    - Material specification, 1948 January 10
    - Material specification - "void"
    - Tool die data, index Spanish mauser rifle
    - Standard practice instruction
    - Material specification, parts lists Colt 45
    - Blueprints, standard operating sheets
    - Operation layouts and equipment lists
    - Miscellaneous documents, tool steel data, drawing rules
    - Drafting room practice
    - Miscellaneous drawing documents
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes
    - Machine tools
    - Federal Adding Machine Corp.
  - 2015-025
    - James B. Colt letter, St. Louis, to Col. Samuel Colt, New York, 1843 December 8
    - James B. Colt letter, Hartford, to Samuel Colt, Paterson, 1840
    - Caroline Colt letter to Samuel Colt, 1844 September 23
    - Tomes, Son & Melbain letter, New York, to Colt Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company, Hartford, 1864 January 16
    - Envelope addressed to Sam Colt, undated